Hello! In today's Bug Bounty Report Explained, you will
learn how you could have stolen private videos
from me or from other YouTube creators. The
vulnerability was reported by David Schutz
and he got $5,000 for it. Links
to his blog post and to his twitter are in the
description. Enjoy! All videos on YouTube have
one of three different visibility attributes:
public, which is self-explanatory, unlisted which
means that someone needs to have the link to the
video to watch it, or private which is also
quite obvious. And the goal of the bug hunter
was to leak the private video of another user. So
he created a second channel with a private video,
copied this video's id and on his first account
he replaced this id in all his requests looking
for insecure direct object references. But turned
out that all endpoints on YouTube were protected
and error messages contained the information
"the video is private". However, Google has many
products with which YouTube integrates. And the
good thing about integrations is that they are
often not as secure as the main product. So the
bug hunter started to look for vulnerabilities
on Google Ads. It's a service that allows YouTube
creators to promote their videos or products.
For example, you can purchase an ad that will be
displayed before someone else's video and when the
customer clicks on the ad he gets redirected
to your video or to your external website.
But if I would create such advertisement I
wouldn't like to publish the 30 seconds video
in your subscription feed, but I'd rather keep
it private. That's why Google Ads needs access
to your private videos. And when creating an
advertisement you can select moments. For example
you can define in which part of your video
company logo or the external link will appear.
And those moments are listed on the right hand
side along with the frame from the selected moment.
This is the request that fetches that
thumbnail every time you create a moment.
Value of 1 is id of the video and value
of 2 is the moment in milliseconds.
Before we continue I have a small announcement.
I've been getting messages that some of you do
not see my videos on YouTube even though
you are subscribed. That's why I created a
mailing list to which you can sign up for free.
You will be notified about my new videos but
also any bonuses or other materials that I may
create in the future. I promise privacy and no spam.
Link is in the description. Okay time
to come back to our vulnerability.
So the researcher replaced the video id with the
video from the second account as many times before.
However, this time it worked. The
response contained base64-encoded frame
from the private video. So it was something,
but stealing one frame has relatively
low impact. Let's see if it was possible to
steal the whole video. With 30 frames per second,
every next frame occurs roughly 33 milliseconds
later. The researcher created a proof of concept
that fetched all the frames from first 3 seconds
of the video. Then, he connected those frames into
a GIF file to see the actual moving video.
This way you can steal whole private videos.
Google paid $5,000 for this
report showing how important it is to them.
However, the attack is a bit limited because you
need to know the video id and leaking this id
would itself be a vulnerability. Moreover, you
can't hear the video and also the resolution
is quite small. Of course, the vulnerability
has been parched and your private videos
are now secure. I think the main takeaway from this
report is that integrations are often less secure
than the main products and impact is still
equally high. Anyway, if you feel like you've
learned something new today leave a like and leave
a subscription. Thanks for watching and goodbye!